const e=JSON.parse(`[{"number":151,"question":"Which of the following animal models is being used as an antidepressant screening tests?","options":{"A":"The learned helplessness model","B":"Reward model","C":"Behavioral despair/forced swim paradigm","D":"Genetic models","E":"All of the above"},"correct_answer":"E","explanation":"The learned helplessness model, reward model, behavioral despair/forced swim paradigm, and genetic models are used in antidepressant screening testing."},{"number":152,"question":"Which of the following is the side effect of mirtazapine?","options":{"A":"Somnolence","B":"Increase in serum cholesterol","C":"Rare incidence of neutropenia","D":"Weight gain","E":"All of the above"},"correct_answer":"B","explanation":"Mirtazapine is associated with side effects including somnolence, increase in serum cholesterol, rare incidence of neutropenia, and weight gain."},{"number":153,"question":"Carbamazepine therapy may be associated with all of the following EXCEPT?","options":{"A":"Decrease in T3 and T4","B":"Decrease in serum cholesterol","C":"Impaired dexamethasone suppression test","D":"False positive pregnancy tests","E":"Risk of skin rash"},"correct_answer":"B","explanation":"Carbamazepine is known to decrease serum T3 and T4, impair dexamethasone suppression test, be associated with false positive pregnancy tests, and possibly increase the risk of skin rash."},{"number":154,"question":"The non-benzodiazepine drug Zolpidem exerts its action by binding to which of the following GABAA receptor units?","options":{"A":"C-alpha Subunit","B":"Alpha -Subunit","C":"β2S-Subunit","D":"γ7-Subunit","E":"None of the above"},"correct_answer":"A","explanation":"Zolpidem is a selective GABAA receptor c^-subunit agonist used in the management of insomnia."},{"number":155,"question":"SSRI-induced sexual side effects can be managed with which of the following medications?","options":{"A":"Aripiprazole","B":"Venlafaxine","C":"Bupropion","D":"Mirtazapine","E":"All the above"},"correct_answer":"C","explanation":"Bupropion by inhibiting dopamine reuptake can increase dopamine function and hence can increase sexual desire and function, reversing SSRI-induced sexual side effects."},{"number":156,"question":"Which of the following is an additive risk factor for the development of renal calculi during Topiramate therapy?","options":{"A":"Coadministration of Acetazolamide","B":"Coadministration of Furosemide","C":"Coadministration of Lithium","D":"Coadministration of Divalproex","E":"All of the above"},"correct_answer":"A","explanation":"Coadministration of acetazolamide, an inhibitor of carbonic anhydrase, increases the risk of renal calculi during Topiramate therapy."},{"number":157,"question":"Which of the following antipsychotic agents may have a role in the development and progression of cataract?","options":{"A":"Risperidone","B":"Olanzapine","C":"Quetiapine","D":"Aripiprazole","E":"Haloperidol"},"correct_answer":"C","explanation":"Quetiapine in higher doses has been associated with cataract formation in beagle dogs."},{"number":158,"question":"Which of the following is used to treat TCA-induced peripheral anticholinergic signs and symptoms?","options":{"A":"Methacholine","B":"Carbachol","C":"Bethanechol","D":"Benztropine","E":"Diphenhydramine"},"correct_answer":"C","explanation":"Bethanechol chloride is used to treat TCA-induced peripheral anticholinergic side effects."},{"number":159,"question":"Which of the following antidepressants is most likely to cause increased sweating as a side effect?","options":{"A":"Bupropion","B":"Mirtazapine","C":"Venlafaxine","D":"Nefazodone","E":"All of the above"},"correct_answer":"C","explanation":"Hyperhidrosis has been associated with antidepressants such as venlafaxine, SSRIs, and Tricyclics."},{"number":160,"question":"Which of the following medications has a role in the management of antidepressant-induced sweating?","options":{"A":"Benztropine","B":"Propranolol","C":"Guanfacine","D":"Lorazepam","E":"All of the above"},"correct_answer":"A","explanation":"Among the agents that are used to treat antidepressant-induced sweating, Benztropine has the most evidence."},{"number":161,"question":"All of the following are antipsychotics belonging to the phenothiazine class EXCEPT:","options":{"A":"Trifluoperazine","B":"Chlorpromazine","C":"Thiothixene","D":"Mesoridazine","E":"Fluphenazine"},"correct_answer":"C","explanation":"Thiothixene is an atypical antipsychotic medication of the thioxanthene class."},{"number":162,"question":"A 29-year-old man with schizophrenia is currently stable on a combination of Aripiprazole and Divalproex sodium. You see him after he has been taking Clarithromycin for 4 days; he appears more anxious and reports worsening tremors and blurred vision. You suspect a drug interaction involving Aripiprazole and erythromycin. The putative DDI involves which of the following cytochrome enzyme?","options":{"A":"CYP2D6","B":"CYP2C9","C":"CYP3A4","D":"CYP2C19","E":"CYP4D"},"correct_answer":"C","explanation":"Clarithromycin is a CYP3A4 inhibitor, and aripiprazole is a substrate for CYP3A4. Hence, coadministration increases aripiprazole concentration."},{"number":163,"question":"Which of the following hematologic abnormalities is seen during clozapine therapy?","options":{"A":"Macrocytosis","B":"Thrombocytopenia","C":"Anemia","D":"Polycythemia","E":"Granulocytopenia"},"correct_answer":"E","explanation":"Granulocytopenia is seen with clozapine therapy."},{"number":164,"question":"Rechallenge of clozapine is not permitted with which of the following counts?","options":{"A":"ANC reaches 2,000 per mm","B":"ANC reaches 1,000 per mm","C":"ANC reaches 1,500 per mm","D":"WBC count reaches 2,000 per mm","E":"WBC count reaches 2,500 per mm"},"correct_answer":"B","explanation":"When ANC reaches 1,000 per mm, clozapine therapy should be discontinued, and rechallenge is not permitted."},{"number":165,"question":"Which of the following drugs inhibits the CYP2D6 isoenzyme?","options":{"A":"Bupropion","B":"Fluvoxamine","C":"Risperidone","D":"Desipramine","E":"Desvenlafaxine"},"correct_answer":"A","explanation":"Bupropion is an inhibitor of CYP2D6 isoenzyme."},{"number":166,"question":"Which of the following drugs strongly inhibits the CYP2D6?","options":{"A":"Bupropion","B":"Fluvoxamine","C":"Risperidone","D":"Desipramine","E":"Fluoxetine"},"correct_answer":"E","explanation":"Fluoxetine strongly inhibits the CYP2D6 isoenzyme."},{"number":167,"question":"Which of the following cytochrome enzymes is more abundant in the gut wall as well as in the liver?","options":{"A":"CYP3A4","B":"CYP2D6","C":"CYP2C9","D":"CYP2C19","E":"CYP2E1"},"correct_answer":"A","explanation":"CYP3A4 is more abundant in the gut wall as well as in the liver."},{"number":168,"question":"P-glycoprotein transport plays an important role in determining blood concentrations and bioavailability of psychotropic drugs. Which of the following statements regarding p-glycoprotein is true?","options":{"A":"Inhibition of p-glycoprotein within the gut wall results in increased drug efficacy","B":"Inhibition of p-glycoprotein within the gut wall results in decreased drug efficiency","C":"Induction of p-glycoprotein within the gut wall results in increased drug efficacy","D":"P-glycoprotein is exclusively located in the plasma membrane of gut lumen","E":"None of the above"},"correct_answer":"A","explanation":"P-glycoproteins mediate distribution and bioavailability of medications. Inhibition of p-glycoprotein within the gut wall results in increased drug efficacy."},{"number":169,"question":"Which of the following drugs antagonizes 5-HT A receptors?","options":{"A":"Mirtazapine","B":"Ziprasidone","C":"Buspirone","D":"Vilazodone","E":"Asenapine"},"correct_answer":"E","explanation":"Asenapine is an antagonist at 5-HT A receptor."},{"number":170,"question":"Which of the following benzodiazepines is not safe in hepatic insufficiency?","options":{"A":"Oxazepam","B":"Lorazepam","C":"Temazepam","D":"Flurazepam","E":"None of above"},"correct_answer":"D","explanation":"Flurazepam is not safe to use in a patient with hepatic insufficiency."},{"number":171,"question":"All of the following are true regarding lithium EXCEPT:","options":{"A":"Comorbid substance abuse is a predictor of poor response to lithium","B":"Lithium is not well tolerated in the elderly population","C":"Lithium is not as effective as anticonvulsants in the treatment of rapid cycling bipolar disorder","D":"Lithium is as effective as antipsychotics in bipolar disorder with comorbid psychotic symptoms","E":"Lithium therapy is not recommended in patients with a history of poor compliance"},"correct_answer":"D","explanation":"Lithium is as effective as antipsychotics in bipolar disorder with comorbid psychotic symptoms."},{"number":172,"question":"A 39-year-old Caucasian man with schizophrenia is on clozapine therapy for the past 2 years. You decide to prescribe Buspirone for his symptoms. All of the following are the potential side effects resulting from the combination of clozapine and Buspirone EXCEPT:","options":{"A":"Thrombocytopenia","B":"Hyperglycemia","C":"GI tract bleeding","D":"Anemia","E":"None of the above"},"correct_answer":"E","explanation":"Coadministration of clozapine and Buspirone increases the risk of GI tract bleeding and hyperglycemia."},{"number":173,"question":"Which of the following psychotropic medications may lead to kidney stones formation?","options":{"A":"Topiramate","B":"Depakote","C":"Lamotrigine","D":"Oxcarbazepine","E":"All of the above"},"correct_answer":"A","explanation":"Topiramate is a carbonic anhydrase inhibitor and hence increases the risk of renal calculi."},{"number":174,"question":"First-pass effect refers to which of the following aspects of a medication's metabolism?","options":{"A":"Redistribution","B":"Lipid solubility","C":"Elimination half-life","D":"Presystemic elimination","E":"Rate of intestinal absorption"},"correct_answer":"D","explanation":"First-pass effect refers to presystemic elimination."},{"number":175,"question":"The risk of teratogenic neural tube defects is greatest for the offspring of mothers taking which of the following anticonvulsants?","options":{"A":"Phenytoin","B":"Lamotrigine","C":"VPA","D":"Levetiracetam","E":"Carbamazepine"},"correct_answer":"C","explanation":"VPA poses the greatest risk of neural tube defects, and it is not recommended in women of childbearing age."},{"number":176,"question":"A 42-year-old Caucasian man is admitted to the emergency department following an overdose of lithium carbonate. What is the most appropriate treatment?","options":{"A":"Sodium bicarbonate IV","B":"Hemodialysis","C":"0.9% Sodium chloride IV","D":"Mannitol IV","E":"Gastric lavage"},"correct_answer":"B","explanation":"Hemodialysis is indicated when lithium levels are high and in patients who are at risk for volume overload."},{"number":177,"question":"The most common side effect during MAO therapy is:","options":{"A":"Sexual dysfunction","B":"Excessive flatus","C":"Postural hypotension","D":"Peripheral edema","E":"Asthenia"},"correct_answer":"C","explanation":"Postural hypotension is the most common side effect of MAOI therapy."},{"number":178,"question":"Clozapine is associated with which of the following cardiovascular effects?","options":{"A":"QTc prolongation","B":"Myocarditis","C":"Cardiomyopathy","D":"Pericarditis","E":"All of the above"},"correct_answer":"E","explanation":"Clozapine is associated with QTc prolongation, myocarditis, cardiomyopathy, and pericarditis."},{"number":179,"question":"Among the following drugs used in mood disorder, which has been most strongly associated with cognitive side effects?","options":{"A":"Lamotrigine","B":"Olanzapine","C":"Topiramate","D":"Carbamazepine","E":"VPA"},"correct_answer":"C","explanation":"Topiramate has been most strongly associated with cognitive side effects."},{"number":180,"question":"Weight gain is not a problem with which of the following antipsychotics?","options":{"A":"Olanzapine","B":"Risperidone","C":"Quetiapine","D":"Molindone","E":"Chlorpromazine"},"correct_answer":"D","explanation":"Molindone causes weight loss."},{"number":181,"question":"All of the following statements regarding clozapine are true EXCEPT:","options":{"A":"Patients are eligible for monthly WBC monitoring after 12 months of continuous therapy with clozapine without any abnormal hematologic counts","B":"The CBC results may not be >7 days old for pharmacist to dispense clozapine","C":"Clozapine is a schedule II drug","D":"In the event that a patient discontinues clozapine, weekly blood work for 4 weeks (minimum) must be performed","E":"Clozapine has an FDA warning for increased risk of death in elderly patients with dementia-related psychosis"},"correct_answer":"C","explanation":"Clozapine is not a schedule II drug."},{"number":182,"question":"What is the maximum recommended daily dose of intramuscular (IM) Ziprasidone?","options":{"A":"60 mg per day","B":"40 mg per day","C":"160 mg per day","D":"100 mg per day","E":"160 mg per day"},"correct_answer":"B","explanation":"The maximum recommended daily dose of IM Ziprasidone is up to 40 mg daily."},{"number":183,"question":"Peak plasma concentrations of IM olanzapine are typically reached in:","options":{"A":"45 to 60 minutes","B":"15 to 30 minutes","C":"60 to 90 minutes","D":"<15 minutes","E":"None of the above"},"correct_answer":"B","explanation":"Peak plasma concentrations of IM olanzapine are typically reached in 15 to 30 minutes."},{"number":184,"question":"All of the following are criteria for treatment-refractory schizophrenia proposed by Kane et al. EXCEPT:","options":{"A":"No episodes of good functioning in the previous 5 years","B":"Total Brief Psychiatric Rating Scale (BPRS) score of >45","C":"Failure to respond to at least three antipsychotic trials from two different chemical class of adequate duration and dose.","D":"Failure to tolerate to a trial of haloperidol","E":"Failure to respond to a trial of long-acting injectable antipsychotic agent"},"correct_answer":"E","explanation":"Failure to respond to a trial of long-acting injectable antipsychotic agent is not one of the proposed criteria for treatment-refractory schizophrenia."},{"number":185,"question":"What dose of fluoxetine has shown to be effective in reducing binge eating and purging in bulimic women?","options":{"A":"10 mg per day","B":"20 mg per day","C":"40 mg per day","D":"60 mg per day","E":"120 mg per day"},"correct_answer":"D","explanation":"Fluoxetine has shown to be effective in reducing binge eating and purging in bulimic women at a dose of 60 mg per day."},{"number":186,"question":"You manage care of a 34-year-old woman with bipolar type II disorder and recently start her on Lamotrigine. In case of interruption of Lamotrigine therapy for 7 days, what is true regarding restarting Lamotrigine?","options":{"A":"In case of interruption of Lamotrigine therapy for 7 days, it requires prior initial start-up dose and gradual re-titration","B":"In case of interruption of Lamotrigine therapy for 2 weeks, it requires prior initial start-up dose and gradual re-titration","C":"In case of interruption of Lamotrigine therapy for >4 weeks, it requires prior initial start-up dose and gradual re-titration","D":"In case of interruption of Lamotrigine therapy, restart to prior initial start-up dose and gradual onset is necessary only when there is a skin rash","E":"None of the above"},"correct_answer":"A","explanation":"Immune tolerance to Lamotrigine is lost after interruption of dosage for >1 week, requiring prior initial start-up dose and gradual re-titration."},{"number":187,"question":"Which of the following is rare, but recognized side effect of clozapine?","options":{"A":"Dilated cardiomyopathy","B":"Myocarditis","C":"Heart failure","D":"Sudden cardiac death","E":"All of the above"},"correct_answer":"E","explanation":"Dilated cardiomyopathy, myocarditis, heart failure, and sudden cardiac death are rare but recognized side effects of clozapine therapy."},{"number":188,"question":"You manage a 31-year-old woman with a history of major depression and BPD with multiple impulsive suicide attempts. You should take all the following precautions EXCEPT:","options":{"A":"Issue prescriptions of short duration","B":"Prescribe multiple but low doses of psychotropic medications","C":"Evaluate the appropriateness of prescribing psychotropic medications in this particular case","D":"Avoid prescribing TCA","E":"None of the above"},"correct_answer":"B","explanation":"Prescribing multiple but low doses of psychotropic medications is not recommended in managing any psychiatric illness."},{"number":189,"question":"Which of the following antidepressants has the most seizurogenic potential?","options":{"A":"Bupropion","B":"Paroxetine","C":"Venlafaxine","D":"Mirtazapine","E":"All of the above"},"correct_answer":"A","explanation":"Bupropion is contraindicated in patients with seizure disorder."},{"number":190,"question":"What is the effect of food on the bioavailability of Ziprasidone?","options":{"A":"Increase in bioavailability","B":"Minimize gastric disease","C":"Decrease in bioavailability","D":"No change in bioavailability of Ziprasidone","E":"None of the above"},"correct_answer":"A","explanation":"Ziprasidone's bioavailability increases by 2-fold when administered with food."},{"number":191,"question":"All of the following drugs have been reported to decrease WBC counts EXCEPT:","options":{"A":"Olanzapine","B":"Mirtazapine","C":"Clozapine","D":"Carbamazepine","E":"None of the above"},"correct_answer":"E","explanation":"Olanzapine, mirtazapine, clozapine, and carbamazepine have all been reported to decrease WBC counts."},{"number":192,"question":"All of the following are true regarding Modafinil EXCEPT:","options":{"A":"Modafinil has reinforcing properties at higher dose","B":"Modafinil is a racemic compound, whose enantiomers have different pharmacokinetics","C":"Modafinil is listed in schedule IV of the Controlled Substances Act","D":"Headache is a common side effect of Modafinil","E":"Modafinil is indicated for narcolepsy"},"correct_answer":"B","explanation":"Modafinil is a racemic compound, and no differences between the enantiomers are reported in animal models."},{"number":193,"question":"Which of the following statements is true regarding venlafaxine and BP elevation?","options":{"A":"The incidence of sustained hypertension with venlafaxine is dose dependent.","B":"The incidence of sustained hypertension with venlafaxine is not dose dependent","C":"The incidence of sustained hypertension is higher with extended release than immediate-release preparation","D":"The BP elevation is transient and will resolve with chronic therapy","E":"All of the above"},"correct_answer":"A","explanation":"Sustained increase in supine diastolic BP is dose dependent. The increase in BP with venlafaxine is not transient."},{"number":194,"question":"Which of the following drugs acts as a GABA-B receptor agonist?","options":{"A":"Diazepam","B":"Zolpidem","C":"Eszopiclone","D":"Baclofen","E":"All of the above"},"correct_answer":"D","explanation":"Baclofen is an agonist at GABA-B receptor."},{"number":195,"question":"Which of the following drugs has the greater evidence for up-regulating neurotrophins including brain-derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF), growth factor, and neurotrophin-3 (NT3)?","options":{"A":"Clozapine","B":"Lithium","C":"Memantine","D":"Vitamin E","E":"Ginkgo biloba"},"correct_answer":"B","explanation":"Lithium has data in upregulating neurotrophins including BDNF, nerve growth factor, and NT3."},{"number":196,"question":"Which of the following agents by virtue of its pro-dopaminergic and neurotrophic effects has shown promise in the treatment of bipolar disorder and unipolar depression?","options":{"A":"Bupropion","B":"Pramipexole","C":"Lithium","D":"Aripiprazole","E":"Clozapine"},"correct_answer":"B","explanation":"Pramipexole is indicated in the treatment of restless leg syndrome and Parkinson disease and is useful in the treatment of depression."},{"number":197,"question":"Which of the following antidepressants has the greatest evidence in the treatment of depression associated with Parkinson disease?","options":{"A":"Nortriptyline","B":"Bupropion","C":"Pramipexole","D":"Sertraline","E":"Venlafaxine"},"correct_answer":"A","explanation":"Nortriptyline has the greatest evidence in the treatment of depression associated with Parkinson disease."},{"number":198,"question":"Which of the following psychiatric drugs has demonstrated efficacy in the treatment of acute and delayed chemotherapy-induced nausea and vomiting?","options":{"A":"Doxepin","B":"Venlafaxine","C":"Fluoxetine","D":"Olanzapine","E":"Aripiprazole"},"correct_answer":"D","explanation":"Olanzapine has demonstrated efficacy in the treatment of acute and delayed chemotherapy-induced nausea and vomiting."},{"number":199,"question":"All of the following are true regarding Selegiline EXCEPT:","options":{"A":"Used for Parkinson disease and depression","B":"It is an MAO-B inhibitor that becomes MAO-A inhibitor at higher doses","C":"SSRIs are contraindicated","D":"Weight loss is reported with Selegiline therapy","E":"None of the above"},"correct_answer":"E","explanation":"Selegiline is used in the treatment of Parkinson disease and depression. It is an MAO-B inhibitor that becomes MAO-A inhibitor at higher doses, and SSRIs are contraindicated."},{"number":200,"question":"A 36-year-old African American male was diagnosed with major depressive disorder with atypical features and was started on Phenelzine with significant benefit. Which of the following should be avoided to prevent hypertensive crisis?","options":{"A":"Amphetamine","B":"Methyldopa","C":"Methylphenidate","D":"Buspirone","E":"All of the above"},"correct_answer":"E","explanation":"Phenelzine when combined with amphetamine, methyldopa, methylphenidate, or buspirone may result in hypertensive crisis."}]`);export{e as default};
